hey guys sh said welcome to concept and
coding and let's start without wasting
any time in our new spring boot video so
till now in jpa we have already seen
that how we are creating our repository
interface right and generally how we are
invoking it from the service class right
so this save find by ID these methods
are already present into the spring
framework right jpa framework and if you
you see our interface we haven't defined
any method but this implementation is
already present but there might be a
requirement where we have to have uh
write our own query right custom query
or you can say that these methods are
not sufficient for you okay so you have
a different or more complex uh query
than just say find by ID so what to do
in that case so today we will go one by
one all such
methods the first is derived
query so what does it do it will
automatically generate queries from the
method okay so we just write method jpa
parts that method and create a query out
of
it need to follow a specific naming
conventions why because see from method
a query is
generated and jpa converts it right so
jpa follows a proper naming convention
so that it can Parts the
method so derive query used for get
remove operation but not for insert and
update because for insert and update
already uh method is present here save
you can use save to insert also to
update also we have already seen that in
the past okay but derive query you can
use it get remove operation and you will
get to know soon why only this so here
if you see there is a Class part three.
Java into an jpa framework if you search
this class you will see a prefix uh you
rejects so this is a rejects so this
rejects so here if you see first is
query
pattern like this then is Count pattern
this okay so all this get uh replaced
here these are just a placeholder so
ultimately this is going to be your
rejects so here if you see that our
method when we are saying that it has to
follow a naming convention so this is it
should follow this rejects then only
your jpa would be able to convert from
method to query so your method should
start with either find or read get query
search
stream count exit delete remove okay so
either one of them method name should
start with either one of these value
okay then the second part comes the
second part says that uppercase letter
like a BC anything you can use okay for
example I have used let's say
find find let's say I'm using find
expense right anything starting with
uppercase letter okay so uppercase
letter anything so here if you see
uppercase letter then I have put dot
star question mark zero or more
characters so I have put expense right
so zero or more characters I have put
after that you have something called
buy okay so this is at the end of your
method so find expense by now after this
what you have to give is the Fe field
name the field name of your entity okay
so it will automatically create
a query out of it it can par it so here
if you
see just see an example in this
repository now I am writing one
method
find okay so this first one I'm choosing
here from the
find then
capital okay then I'm uppercase letter
I'm using capital u then s r anything
like I want to give anything so here
it's like zero or more characters right
so I'm just using find user
details then
bu find user details by now here if you
see this
thing this thing ultimately after buy
whatever you will write it will like
wear Clause okay so this should be your
entity field name so this is my entity
user details inside that field name is
name okay so it just follows like uh
camel letter so uh n is capital so name
okay and
here in the parameter we have like what
the name it should come so it will
automatically generate a query like this
select
all the data from the user table user
details table from this user details
where username equals to this so this
question mark will get replaced with
this but now here if you see that we
haven't wrote any J uh jpql or SQL query
we haven't written any query we just
written
method but jpa internally Parts it into
a query
that's why this is known as derived
query okay from method query is
generated okay that is done by jpa not
by us and this method should follow a
naming convention like
this so let's say different use cases so
that you can understand more better
about this uh derived query so now here
see this method name which which I have
written here so
find okay user details by now I'm using
name and phone so if you open that part
tree. Java you will see all this parsing
logic where like and or wherever it is
present there itself so now here after
buy you know that it would be a we
Clause where then we have a name so this
is all the fields now now okay so where
name equals to this and
your and your phone equals to replace
with this so that query would be
generated so and okay similarly or also
we can use so now here see what I'm
using by name and phone or user ID so
the similarly it will get translated to
query name and phone
or user
ID
okay then we have something called
comparison so the query can be so many
things right so see if you open the
part. Java class there is an enum list
so because in the query we can have
between is not null is null less than
less than equals to greater than
everything right so that's where we have
all this enum present which we can write
into the method so if you want to use
let's say between so either you can
write between in the method or is
between both are both will work uh jpa
would be able to catch
both okay so these are all the kind of
different comparisons or uh different
enums which is also present so let's say
that here I'm using find user detail by
name okay and I'm putting is in okay
after the field you can use
anything it will just interpret like
this
from this name field okay where name
field what we wanted is is in okay so we
are since we are using in that's why the
parameter acceptor
list okay so username in and this
whatever the list will go go inside
this okay similarly you can use like
also okay like name
like okay then whatever the name would
we have let's say string name so the
similarly query would be generated like
this I hope this is clear right so this
is
like jpa already has given us what else
we can use in a method since we
generally do not aware of this we find
complicate to write a derived query uh
but here jpa has given us everything
like uh what should be the syntax we
should follow and uh like in query what
all things we can use I am totally agree
also you might be thinking like we it is
difficult to write a complex queries yes
derived query is generally for uh not we
can't write two complex queries right
like join and all so it's just like
like if you don't have that much complex
but little custom requirement but
simpler queries yeah we can go ahead
with the derived query
itself
okay so here I using by name like and
the name so now here if you see it got
interpreted like
this similarly now see we are using
delete method so now whenever we going
to use delete method so now we are
updating the DB something so that's why
we also have to use at the rate
transactional on top of your method
which you going to write so delete I am
using you know right we can start with
delete right and bu I want to delete by
name and this is the
name so here this query ultimately
delete query would be generated like
this okay so it it's going to delete by
name so now let's say this you have
let's say um name you want to delete a
so if there are 10 entries with the name
a so that many times delete it will
call okay so all entries it will delete
it
okay we can also uh look at the
pagination and sorting in derived query
which is also very important so jpa has
two interfaces to support pagination and
sorting one is pageable this is one
interface which through which we can uh
do pagination another is sort through
which we can achieve
sorting okay so the pageable interface
right through this we can set two things
page number and Page
size okay you we all know pagination
right uh so let's say you have 10
records you have 10
records uh in the page page number start
from zero 0 1 2 3 like this goes and
let's say the page size you have given
like in one page number of record should
be let's say five so in the page zero
you have five records page one you have
five records so total 10 records so two
pages are
there okay similarly we can use like
this so whatever the derive method you
are writing okay so I'm using find I
think now you can interpret right what
what the query is going to be created
find so means it's a select query this
is optional user details by name
starting with starting with right so
it's like something like this this is
the name you are going to use so this is
your
username and there you can provide your
pageable object uh parameter see there
is no such sequence that pageable should
be come at last it should come at Mid or
it should come as this one uh generally
it jpa Parts the method so it knows that
pageable parameter so it will treat it
like this so generally as a convention I
would say that always try to uh put
pageable uh parameter at the last itself
okay so that it's always like a
convention but there are no such harsh
and fast rule that pageable should be at
the the last itself it can be in the mid
also so jpa can interpret it
properly so now here if you see that in
this uh pageable parameter in the method
derived method itself we can write it
now in the service
class when we are calling this method
name we have to pass this pageable right
so now here if you see that this is our
interface pageable now I creating page
request. off
page number I want zero page and in the
what should be the page size five okay
so that I wanted page zero and in the
one page the five entries can be present
so that I wanted and I pass
this okay so if you have you already
know that if you have seven entries one
2 3 4 5 6 7 so 1 2 3 4 5 this will go
into page zero
and in the page one six and seven would
be there only two okay because there are
to only seven entries
only if we need more info about Pages
whether it's a first page whether it's a
last page or if there are more page then
we can use page as a return type so now
here if you see
currently okay from this one I am
returning the list of user detail
itself okay
but if I need more
detail I would use page object right in
the return type okay so now this page
how we can use now here I am getting
this when I call in the service class I
got this return type now page this one
from there I can get more details so
first I need to get the content so from
this page I do get content I will get
this list whatever the output I'm
getting from the DB
the same object I can use it like hey
what are the total number of pages is
this is my first page is this is the
last page is last right so you will get
uh more info from if you required then
you can return type us this page so this
is just an example I have total six
entries in the DB starting with all a
okay because my method is say start with
and I am passing a so my query would be
like something like this
okay and here I'm returning zero and
page five so 1 2 3 4 5 e till here I
would get it six and uh this I would get
into the next
page if I do one five then I would get
into this last
one
okay okay so there is also one more
thing like page ination with sorting
also it's
possible so when we are creating a
pageable object right page request dot
of the page number the page
size then there is also an interface I
told you right sort interface we have so
we can do sort
by we can give
properties we can give more than one
properties I will tell you uh but let's
say that currently I want to sort by
only one field that is name this is an
entity whatever the Java entity object
which we have it's a its field name it's
field name not DB column anything entity
Java entity field name okay so sort. by
and we have the property where we will
provide the list of
fields currently I'm giving only one
field that is name and I want to sort it
into a descending
order and similarly the pageable I am
passing into my
method okay and now here if you see that
I am trying to F page zero and the page
size is five so here I am getting into
the descending order because I I have
given the order sorting by
descending we can only use sorting also
we don't if you don't want pagination
and only want to use sorting then you
don't you just need this sort right you
don't just need uh page pageable so that
also is possible so here in the same
method it can also accept this sort
interface and in the service class you
just provide sort by the same thing sort
by whatever the field you want to sort
and descending order and you will get
the
output The sort. Bu except multiple
Fields see that when multiple fields are
provided sorting applied in
order okay let's say that I provided by
name comma
phone so what would happen is let's say
I have two entries a A or three entries
a a a and its phone number is one phone
number is two phone number is
three so now here if you see that first
and I want want it like descending
order now here if you see that name is
all three same so what it will do is
after that it use the second field phone
so now phone it will use it and now will
will store in a descending order so a a
a phone is in three phone 2 phone 1 now
this would be the Sorting so you got it
so first is sort by the first field and
if there are duplicate then second field
is used and so on you can give multiple
field like this sort by you can comma
separated multiple Fields you can give
so it will first try to sort with this
if there are duplicates then it will use
second fields to sort it and like so
on this is just an example Ive tried to
explain but there might be a question
that hey what if we need different
sorting order for different fields it's
possible
right uh for name I want
ascending for phone I want
descending but with this one sort. bu
since all the fields are in one and we
are just either ascending or descending
it's not possible so there is another
way we can do it like similar way sort.
bu now for each field for each field we
have to provide an order sort. order
ascending the field name sort. order
descending and the
phone okay and the same sort interface
we will give here so with this for each
field we can have different kind of
sorting either ascending and
descending now I have already told you
that if the queries are little
complex then using deriv D method
derived query whatever you can say it's
little bit tough you have to think a lot
that okay find then I have used buy then
name then greater than then like how you
will do that sometime it become more
greater okay so it can't be handled by a
derive query then what next then here we
have something called
jpql Java persistence query
language similar to SQL but works on
entity object SQL works on database
database table name column name but here
it works on jpql works on entity object
so in Java you have a class right let's
say user so it works on this maybe this
is correspond to a table user but
understand that JPL understand this so
whatever the name of the class is that
whatever the fields names is it work on
that one instead of direct database
and because of that it's database
independent so today you have let's say
my
SQL tomorrow you want to change it and
you want to use postgress it doesn't
matter jpql is jpql is using the class
okay what beneath database you are using
doesn't care so that's why it is known
as database independent you can change
database you want your queries will
remain the same because it is dependent
on your ENT
entity okay so the same thing it's work
with the entity name and field not with
table
names so understand this one simple
query of the jpql it will give you a
better
Clarity so in the same repository
interface class like whatever the name
you want to give now this name is not
should be like find by don't get
confused that find by should be there
you can use anything right now we have
to provide our query jpql query so we
have to use annotation at theate query
and inside this we have to give the
jpql the query so it is very very
similar to SQL only very sorry very very
similar to SQL select instead of estess
you just provide the object or you can
say that alas of your entity user detail
is my uh class right entity class user
details so I have alas is U right so the
same U I am using here so it is
equivalent to estess if you want a
specific field you do U do let's say
name comma U do phone like this like an
object from instead of table name your
entity class entity name okay this is an
alas where
now this is your field name U do name
okay it is your field name entity field
name not column
name name equals
to so in this
method like whatever the parameter you
are getting if you have a dynamic value
you can you have to map it right so
that's why I'm using add theate param
okay you can give this param some name
you can give anything name and the same
name you have to use it here okay so
this name and this name should be
matching and then this parameter get
ultimately replaced
here okay so U do name equals
to and whatever the parameter which we
have to bind we have to use it like this
so in the method at theate param user
first name I have given the same I have
used here
and the parameter
name okay so it binds method parameter
with the named parameter in the query so
it will
bind this
username okay this atate param and this
one
binds username with this one named query
parameter also there is no restrict
strict rule for the return type you can
ask what should be the return
type can I have a list can I have only
one object that depends upon what query
you are writing let's say your query can
accept or return only uh let's say that
only one one row
but but ultimately and you have like
written like this user detail
find uh find name something and you have
written your query but now when this
query ultimately runs let's say if it
return more than one row but your return
type is only one object then it will
throw an
exception so the return type you have to
select yourself whether this query is
going to return me a list whether this
query is going to return me only one
object so you have to use it
appropriately okay but let's say that if
there are more than one rows but in
return type is single object then there
is an
exception so see jpql with the join how
it works very very simple very very
similar to SQL join itself so see one to
one uh ver annotation like how we can
use it so you know that already we have
seen the mapping one to one how we can
create it so I have just user detail
user address one user can have only one
address so that's why I have put this
mapping one to one mapping now see how I
am writing a join query with the
jpql whatever the method name you want
to give you can give doesn't so don't
get confused with the derived query you
whatever you want you can give it so
here if you see I not using buyer
anything so whatever you want to give so
select UD UD is user details I have
given an alas uh UD so all select all
the fields of a user detail
from this user detail
entity now I want to join so now here if
you see this user detail has a
relationship with the user address so
this field so UD dot user
address okay so now generally in SQL you
have right table
one
join table
two on
right table 1 do certain column equals
to table 2 do certain column generally
we have in this SQL so table one we have
already kind of an entity
here join table two it's like in the
entity we have like user detail do
address okay we don't have to provide
jpql in this on jpql will automatically
add it because it knows that that entity
how the foreign key we have maintained
in the
entity okay so that's why there is no on
here okay and directly we ultimately
adding where whatever we
wanted so now here if you see when the
query get
translated so select all the fields of
user
details from table one user details join
table two user unor address
okay on automatically it jpa added
because we are working with entity not
directly table so here jpa knows that
how this two tables are associated one
to one it knows the mapping which column
and uh in user detail and which column
in user address so that's where it does
automatically add a on for us and after
that we Clause is
added okay
so you can also see one more thing
now you might have a requirement that
hey I don't want to return all the
fields of one entity I just want to
return like some fields of user detail
and some fields of user address okay
then what should be the return type
looks like for a method so this is the
repository in this repository you have
to create a method like this okay now
here if you see in the select query of
the jpql my return type is one field
from user detail name and another from
address table I want to return only
country okay now let's say that if this
query where name equals to user first
name okay where ud. name equals
to first name so we are uh binding like
this we already seen that so this could
return multiple rows right each row
contains name comma
country name comma country name comma
country so here if you see it's a list
of object
array list of list of object
array okay so now here if you see when
I'm calling this method and passing that
name whatever I am getting a list of
object array now in the code you can
pass it you can iterate over the list
now you know that okay the first field
is a string pass it the string second
field is also string Parts is
string okay and you might have to now
put into a custom dto so I have create
One D with like name and the country and
you can simply uh return this by
creating a list of the dto and return
it okay so that is one way but you might
be sometimes uh thinking that hey this
object array doesn't looks good right uh
can we have something better so here if
you see that from that object array we
are creating our user dto right we are
filling this list of dto we can directly
do here itself okay we can directly do
here itself we don't have to return an
object array we can even return the list
of user D2 itself okay so see this one
now
select okay what I am returning I am
creating a new object new the complete
path of your user
dto okay and whatever the value which is
coming from the query name and the
address I am passing it's like a
Constructor it's just like you are
creating a new object right new user dto
and in the Constructor you are passing
the values it just the same thing it
just we have to provide a complete path
okay and this value is coming from the
tables
like the entity columns whichever we
wanted if you are
returning four rows like from this query
right for each query it will create a
new object new dto and whatever the
values it is coming from your query like
this one object here one object here and
it will ultimately create a list of this
one
okay now this is very important like
there is one when we talk about one to
many and many to many there is one issue
comes is n+ one
problem it is very frequently Asked in
an interview questions also okay I I'll
tell you it's not that hard but yeah
there is something like this itself
so see the query wise whether it's one
to one or one to
many the query wise there is no change
so now here if you see that I'm creating
one too many user detail can have
multiple address one user can have many
addresses so I just changed one to one
to one to many we already seen that how
to do that it's very simple right and
the queries also Remains the Same okay
select all the fields of a user detail I
am putting a join the join is with user
detail list ud. user detail list right
there there is no need required of on it
already knows that where the name is
this okay so I'm trying I'm searching my
I'm doing a search on the user
detail where the name is whatever that's
coming into this method and it will
ultimately do a join at fetch all the
list of user addresses
also
okay now here if you see
that it's this query can result into n+
one
problem
how the query wise it's exactly the same
first see what happen if you
remember we learned something about
eager initialization and lazy
initialization
okay with now let's say that you have a
parent and you have multiple
Childs child one child 2 child
three with
lazy it first fetches the parent only
and when we are trying to access its
child then only it will try to find all
its
child and in the eager what we have seen
till now is when you have a multiple
Childs and you are using eager it will
at the first when you're trying to find
a parent itself it will automatically
also load the child
itself but remember one use case where
eager does not work in this manner let's
say that you have a
query so this is multiple parents this
is multiple each parent has multiple
Childs each each parent has multiple
Childs if your query
is query is like is
fetching one parent and multiple
child eager will work like this what we
have
seen let's say it will fetch this and
all its child also but if your query is
like it can
fetch multiple par
and also multiple
child okay if your query is such that it
can fetch multiple
parent right and for each parent
multiple child also then your eager does
not work like what we have seen okay so
how it works is
that let's say I'll tell you in a simple
way you have two user two parent parent
one parent two okay and and it has three
child this also has three child and we
have created a query that which is
matching both the parents okay so what
how the query will run like
this first
query it will
fetch all the
parents okay so here with this we'll get
parent one and parent 2
okay now it will
create two different query one for
parent one to fetch its
Childs and another query is for parent
two to fetches all its
Childs okay so just now imagine instead
of this two just imagine there are
n and each parent have any number of
child
so if your query is like it can fetch n
number of parents so one query it
required it will fetch n number of
parent parent 1 parent 2 parent
n okay one query is to fetch n number of
parents then n number of time it will
run for each parent and it will fetch
all its Childs parent one Childs parent
two
Childs like this parent and Childs so
one query plus n queries the total n+
one
query it will hit to fetch all the
data you got it like the only the
scenario when you have multiple your
query can fetch multiple parent and each
parent have multiple child then because
of performance issue
the jpa does like this okay it eagerly
doesn't work like okay for each parent
it automatically goes and fetch all the
child in the start itself no okay first
it will only fetch all the parents and
then let's say that you are doing get
child for each parent it will create it
will hit the N number of queries to for
each parent it will get the child so
this this the same thing I have
explained here now say I have one
user can have many
address and our query is such that it
can fetch more than one user more than
one user mean more than one parent it
can fetch then only this can problem can
occur so say we have n users then below
query hit by jpa is one query to fetch
all the
users okay so one query you will fetch
user one user two user n right
and each user can have multiple Childs
so for each user now it will hit and
fetch it Childs user to child so
similarly n times it will fetch so total
n query so total n+ one hit it will
do so we need to find a way so that one
query only hit instead of n+ one or any
better performance than
this before going to the solution for
this problem one thing might be coming
to a point is why not eager
initialization I've already explained
you before that eager initialization
only works when you are like only one
your query is fetching only one parent
and even though it have multiple child
doesn't matter it will go even if you're
trying to fetch one parent it will
automatically go ahead and create a
query such that it will also fetch its
child also and if you remember we all
did a testing by find by ID so means
only one parent we are only getting but
as soon as you made a query such that
multiple parents are possible
eager initialization won't work because
of performance
issue okay so here you can uh see this
an example I have very simple use case I
have created two username both AA okay
okay and they have uh this also user ID
one also has certain child user ID to
also has certain child I have kept only
one one they can have multiple child at
now see my query how it is that
select all the roles from the user
detail join the user address list where
name equals to user first name okay and
the in the what I have given in the
query AA so
now my query can user details you can
see that multiple parent rows can come
for each parent rows there can be
multiple children's row so how this
works is that it it fetch me the data
but how the queries it will hurt is the
first
query it didn't do eager initialization
right so here it first fetches only the
user detail all the user it fetch all
the user detail itself see user
ID right all the user ID details like
what we have commanded over
here now for each user
it is hitting so I have two users right
so for this id1 it is fetching its child
for ID user so this is for user one this
is for user two it is again fetching it
child so now here if you see address
details okay so now for each user it is
making a select query so two queries it
is making so Total 1 + 2 total three
queries
Okay so that's why it is known as 1 plus
n issue so is like n number of parents I
have so that many plus one to fetch all
the
parents so how to solve this n plus1
problem one thing is so there are
different ways we have seen that
earlier uh we are using
derived query we are using jpql and also
when we were not using both right our
repository is empty
it's empty we are using
inbuild so in all the scenarios we
should be able to handle the N plus1
problem one thing is using join fetch
instead of simple join we can use join
fetch so this fetch join
fetch tell specifically to jpql
that make only one
query okay so here if you see that
the it changes the query okay even
though I have written only user details
here select user details only but the
query it created is that it has user
details it also has the address
also and is joining properly it is
fetching for all the users it is
fetching its all the child itself in the
one query
itself okay so it's like enforcing
maybe
here you are trying to fetch only
users right that's why that's why
earlier it created only this query
because I'm trying to fetch only user
details so it won't fetch address
details right it's just trying to fetch
me the user details and this select
queries because in the return type maybe
Json parser is trying to fetch the
address details so that's where it hit
and F fetch for each
user but when you use join fetch it the
preand itself it says that okay even
though we have provided user detail hey
fetch all the respective child details
also beforehand itself so only one query
it
hit the second solution is that using at
theate batch size right and we can
provide the size so here okay let's say
that we are not using anything derived
or jpql okay we are using normal like
earlier how we used to see we have
provided a relationship but we can
provide here at the bat size size equals
to
10 so here what it will do is that
yes first even though I am using eager
okay and I am trying to hit a query
where
hey find all
find all user give me find all the user
let's say so what it will do is
that even though I have made it
eager I can have multiple users right so
it first
always go with the okay get me all the
users
itself okay once it get me all the
users okay now here it will make
the child query but now here in this
case it will use the
batch okay so it will
reduce it will reduce the select queries
and it won't make like n + one but it
will or it won't be like only one it
won't reduce it from n+ 1 to one but you
can say that it will reduce
it from this n plus1
itself right because now here if you see
that we are fetching in bul in the
batch fetch all the user details in
batch instead of one one one user for
each user one fet child user two fet
child now here if you see that we are
let's say for 10 users we are fetching
in a single shot so maybe we are
reducing
some queries
hit okay so that is one way of doing it
another is using at theate entity graph
this is generally helpful in the derive
method in the derived method actually we
are not writing at theate query where we
can put join fetch right so in derived
method generally we can use this at
theate entity graph and here in the
attribute we can provide the child
table for which we have to fetch all the
details whenever we are trying to load
the parent as simple as it is okay so
means whenever I am fetching user detail
hey in a single shot also fetch all the
users also okay even though you have
even though my query is like fetching
three users at a time fetch it children
also in the single
shot okay so everything depends upon
query how we are writing the query so
jpa does internally some optimization
right so don't get confused in this
right when your query is fetching only
one user okay and it has multiple child
why it is creating a query with the join
properly and fetching user plus its
child but as soon as your query is like
multiple Childs which can have multiple
children why it is returning only this
users detail why not CH jpa has certain
this optimization try that uh because it
we know that only three it will return
JP doesn't know that so for optimization
purpose it by default it say that okay I
will only fetch user if you required me
to fetch child also do that okay then
only then it goes at for each user it
will try to F the children details
itself on demand basis okay but if you
enforce it like entity graph or through
best size or through this joint fet you
are enforcing hibernate you can say that
jpa that hey go ahead don't try to
optimize it no matter how many users is
also fetches children
also
okay so how to join many pro many tables
so let's say table a has relationship
with table B table B has relationship
with table C doesn't matter with j pql
like how you are how we are writing in
SQL right the same thing uh jpql exactly
same let's say that uh from this is your
table a join a dobl list so this is your
table B
join B do this is your table C so like
this you can increase on join and you
don't need on Clause that's all and
whatever the we Clause you want you can
use it
as simple as it
is then there is something called at
theate modifying annotation this is very
interesting the jpql whenever you are
writing any query the by default
assumption is that you are going to
write a select
query okay so now let's say that I have
written one delete or insert or add
update query inside at
theate query I have trying to insert
delete
something now if I run this it will
throw me an error that hey expecting a
select query by default jpql expecting a
select query
only so we have to use this annotation
at theate modifying
above at theate query one your query
here and we are telling the JPI that hey
expect either delete or update
or insert query which is modifying the
database
okay so this annotation is used to tell
jpa that accept either delete insert or
update
query so we are trying to update the DB
so definitely with this three we have to
use the at theate transactional
also okay so like this the same query we
can write it but since now it is delete
we have to use atate modifying and at
theate transactional also
now there is one very interesting
question also comes on top of it the
usage of flush and clear like now we are
using we are updating the DB with the
jpql okay
so we have
data in persistent context
also so how it impacts I will tell you
so first understand the difference
between flush and clear
so you have let's say persistence
context you already know that
persistence contact it's like a first
level caching and then you have DB let's
say in DB you have entity uh table a and
here also persistent contact you have
entity table a okay here you have some
value one here it has value two let's
say because we are working on it we
might be updating it so when you do
flush so flush means push the changes of
persistence context it's like a
committing change it to two it's like
committing but it do not delete the
persistence context data when you do
clear persistence context clear so it
will remove it like remove this state of
this a it is now not managing it
okay why I'm telling you this okay so
here consider this use case
now so I am just saying that I am using
add theate modifying and I'm using at
theate query I'm trying to delete some
data from the DB and at theate
transaction I am using at the service
layer and what I'm doing is first let's
say uh you have a table
user uh user ID let's say
one so first I am doing find by user
ID okay find and you know that when
whenever I will do a find it will put
into person persistence context now
persistence context has id1
also now second I'm doing delete by
username so I'm calling this in the same
so it is in the same sequence happening
right so I'm deleting the DB now so this
data is deleted but now data is present
into persistence context now I am doing
find by ID will I get the data output
present is it
present true
it's present because now when you're
trying to do find it will not hit the DB
it will return from here itself
persistence Contex and data is present
here so if your use case is that
whenever I am updating the DB my
persistence contacts also get updated
properly so in the
modifying we have to make flush
automatically equals to True clear
automatically equals to True flush means
whatever the data is present into the
persistence context
update and then clear it
also
okay so now if you do
that what we are getting first we have
like say
here DB id1 here we have a persistence
context id1 let's say because we did a
first find then we did by delete we
deleted it and then we are doing when we
deleted it we also put modifying flush
true we haven't modified anything so
there is nothing need to update clear
automatically equals to true so it will
remove the data from persistance Context
now when you're trying to fetch from the
that it will try to not uh fet from Pur
C it will try to hit from DB and does
value present now no
false okay so if the question arise
right when you are using at the
modifying with jpql how you
are uh managing the data in the
persistence context we can say that by
clear automatically and flush
automatically setting it to
true and also pagination and sorting in
jpql is exactly similar what we have
seen in the derived query so whatever
the method you are writing where you are
putting at theate query in the same
method like uh you just put at theate
pageable and also sort if you want and
the same in the service you can pass it
like in the derive we are passing it so
no change in that it will work as it is
so pagination and sorting is exactly the
same now there is one more concept
called at theate named query annotation
so as the name says that we can name our
query so that we can reuse it let's say
that if you have any use case where a
same query is used at multiple places in
your code so instead of duplicating it
we can write the query into one place
using at theate name query we can give
it a name and in our code base we can
use that name
directly so generally whatever the
entity class which we have in that we
write this ad theate name query whatever
the query which you have to write write
it
here again it's a jpql for now and you
can give it a name like this find by
username you can give any name okay so
on top of entity you have to use it like
this given a name and the query
whichever you want to
write now in the repository or anywhere
a different repository of user okay
whatever the method you have at the top
you have to write the at theate query
right you now you don't have to write
the query you can just use name find by
username so it will automatically use
this query
itself right and the same name you can
use at multiple places in your code base
so that you don't have to duplicate your
query and in future if any change in the
query you have to make you have to make
it only one
place
okay so that's uh I hope that's the
purpose of it clear so in next video
I'll tell you about criteria API
specification
API and Native
query okay and some other topics but
yeah uh that's pretty much uh sorry
because jpa is going uh so many parts
there are so many content uh or so many
Topic in JP I don't want to skip any
part so please be with me and I
hopefully in the next part n itself I
will complete it okay guys see you soon
bye